# SHUBHAM BOMBARDE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+91 8149136545 shubhambombarde4@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/shubhambombarde github.com/shubhambombarde

shubhambombarde.vercel.app

Pune, India

I am a seasoned Software Developer with nearly 5 years of expertise in crafting exceptional frontend features using React (Next JS), GraphQL, and TypeScript. My curiosity for exploring the realm of AI, coupled with my proficiency in technical domains, consistently contributes to the enhancement of product quality and user experience. I excel in collaborative environments, communicating complex concepts effectively.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend - React, NextJS, TypeScript, React Query, Redux, Cypress, Storybook

Animation - Framer Motion, CSS

AWS - Cognito, Appsync, CaptchaPython - Django & flask, Machine Learning

## **PUBLICATION**

 Published thesis in Springer titled "Livability- Analysis of People's Living Comfort in Different Cities of India Using GIS: A Prototype" (ref <a href="https://www.link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-46540-7\_5">https://www.link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-46540-7\_5</a>)

### WORK EXPERIENCE

March 2024 - Present

# **Software Engineer**

### Vistra

- Engineered a comprehensive client onboarding and management platform from the ground up for corporate services. Helped onboard over 3000 clients in first two quarters.
- Centralized data from diverse sources into a unified, authoritative platform, employing advanced strategies with **ReactFlow** to deliver intuitive, visually appealing UI.
- Integrated a customized Gen-Al model via **AWS Bedrock** to elevate user experience and operational efficiency.
- Spearheaded performance optimisations, ensuring seamless interactions and responsiveness across the platform, enhancing both code efficiency and user engagement.

### Zuju Digital, Singapore - Gamifying football fan experiences

- Engineered high-performing, user-friendly front-end features for the user application and back-office systems, resulting in user satisfaction improvement and a 30% increase in operational efficiency.
- Worked closely with UX/UI designers to translate design wireframes into responsive, and animations into interactive web applications.
- Orchestrated seamless integration and maintained platform consistency by collaborating with cross-functional teams, comprising backend developers and designers. Proactively identified communication misalignments, resulting in a remarkable 20% reduction in development time.
- Boosted website traffic by **4x** by using a dynamic sitemap and pre-building associated pages in streamlined pipeline to minimise latency.
- Continuous learning, proactively made recommendations for tech stack enhancements, such as advocating for the adoption of Static page generation to optimize load times (~30% faster) and overall system efficiency.

# Software Engineer TOKIGAMES, Singapore

March 2021 - March 2022

- Developed robust and efficient front-end code for the company's platform, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Implemented and optimized the user app, enhancing its performance and ensuring its alignment with business objectives (~50% faster).
- Proactively identified and resolved bottlenecks and bugs, employing strategic problem-solving techniques to minimize system downtime and enhance overall performance.
- Contributed to the creation and upkeep of documentation (70% coverage), assisting in onboarding new team members and serving as a knowledge base for ongoing development.

# Software Engineer Searce, India

July 2019 - February 2021

- Developed and maintained a robust platform for a movie production company, facilitating real-time tracking of progress, financials, and pre-production planning. This helped them move 60% of their unorganised data into our centralised platform.
- Collaborated closely with an overseas client, providing them with vital development assistance, and ensuring their project met stipulated benchmarks and quality standards.
- Played a key role in the digital transformation of a traditional newspaper agency, spearheading their transition to a web-based platform. Over 55% of the user-base migrated and continued using the online platform.

### EDUCATION

# PGD in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence

2020 - 2021

IIIT, Bangalore, India

### **Bachelor in Computer Engineering**

2015 - 2019

MIT Academy of Engineering, Pune, India

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving Critical Thinking Decision Making Attention to Detail